SRI HARSHA CHILAKAPATI

Bengaluru, India · +91 9494607964

 $sriharshachilakapati@gmail.com \cdot goharsha.com \cdot github.com/sriharshachilakapati$

A self-enthusiast developer who is interested in developing applications for platforms of interest such as Android, Web, Desktop and also iOS. Had experience in building real-time applications optimized for performance. I'm always interested in exploring tech.

EXPERIENCE

1ST OCTOBER 2019 - PRESENT

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT ENGINEER

JUSPAY

- Optimized Gradle build pipeline to make builds faster by 65% from 2 minutes to 13 seconds.
- Created new SDK architecture for Hyper SDK 2.0, a flagship product of Juspay.
- Created a Chrome DevTools plugin which allows debugging of native Android Views.
- Wrote 2 Gradle plugins to generate code and assets for merchants resulting in reduction of merchant specific flavours in the HyperSDK code base.

1ST JUNE 2018 – 30TH SEPTEMBER 2019

ASSOCIATE SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT ENGINEER

JUSPAY

- Part of the payment page team and worked on payment pages for Ola Money, Cred and Big Basket.
- Took ownership of Payment Pages for Foodpanda and Bounce (Android & iOS).
- Created the VIES merchant demo app (Android) at Juspay.

4TH DECEMBER 2017 – 31ST MAY 2018

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT ENGINEERING INTERN

JUSPAY

- Implemented 2 screens (Settings & User Profile) in BHIM UPI App.
- Part of the 4-person team and created the first payment page prototype for Goibibo.
- Worked on Android module of Presto UI called Mystique, which is a React Native like framework for Juspay.

3RD MAY 2017 - 9TH JUNE 2017

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING INTERN

MIRACLE SOFTWARE SYSTEMS

- Created a Help Desk ticketing system for company employees using Material Design in a team of 6.
- It uses NLP APIs from IBM Watson to analyze the tone of the message and decides ticket priority based on keywords.

JUNE 2017 – 30TH NOVEMBER 2017

TEACHING ASSOCIATE, SVEC TECHNICAL CLUB

PROJECTS

- SilenceEngine (Game Engine for Desktop, HTML5 and Android)
- WebGL4J (WebGL bindings for Java language using GWT)
- GWT-AL (An OpenAL implementation on top of Web Audio API)
- YT Private Subscriptions (iOS App that allows to subscribe to YT channels without logging in)
- <u>EasyJSON (Easy to use small (11 KB) JSON</u> <u>library for Java)</u>
- EasyXML (Easy to use small (13 KB) XML library for Java)

SKILLS

PROFICIENT IN

Java, Kotlin, JavaScript, Swift, PureScript, Android Development, iOS Development

FAMILIAR WITH

C, C++, C# and 24 other Programming Languages

CAN COMMUNICATE IN

Telugu, English, Hindi, Kannada, Tamil

EDUCATION

NOV 2021

SYSTEMS EXPERT, ALGOEXPERT.IO

MAY 2021

IOS DEVELOPER NANODEGREE, UDACITY

FEB 2021

ANDROID KOTLIN DEVELOPER NANODEGREE, UDACITY

EXPECTING IN 2021

B. TECH IN COMPUTER SCIENCE, SVEC